Finding Aid for the Paul Des Marais Music Manuscripts PASC-M.0177
UCLA Library Special Collections
Paul Des Marais music manuscripts
1947-1993
UCLA Library Special Collections
Des Marais, Paul
PASC-M.0177
1.0 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
This collection consists of manuscripts and ozalid masters of scores
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Paul Des Marais; gift; 1998, 1999.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942357953606533
Biography
Des Marais by born on June 23, 1920, in Menominee, MI.; studied with Leo Sowerby in Chicago; BA (1949), MA (1953), Harvard Univ., where he studied with Nadia Boulanger and Walter Piston; taught composition at the University of California, Los Angeles from 1960; works include the operas Epiphanies (1964-8) and Le cimetière marin (1971), two piano sonatas (1947, 1952), music for various vocal and instrumental ensembles, and incidental music for theatrical and dance productions.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of manuscripts and ozalid masters of scores of compositions by Paul Des Marais.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Collection is arranged chronologically.
Composers -- United States -- Archives.; Music -- Manuscripts.; Des Marais, Paul--Archives.
- Sonata for piano (1947). Ozalid masters, black ink, 27 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Piano Sonata in G (1952). Ozalid masters, blank ink, 37 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  "To Robert Moevs." Dated "Peterborough, New Hampshire, 1-31 July, 1952."
- Theme and changes: for harpsichord (1953). Ozalid masters, black ink, 16 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  "Written for and dedicated to Sylvia Marlowe"--title page. Dated "July, Peterborough, 1953."
- For the time being: Two choral excerpts. Ozalid masters, black ink, 21 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  I. At the Manger; II. Chorus (Finale). "1955, Boston.. With the permission of Mr. W. H. Auden."--title page. For chorus and three pianos.
- Motet in three movements: for mixed voices, cellos and double basses (1959). Ozalid masters, black ink, 33 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  1. Denaill; 2. Vertue; 3. Discipline. Poems by George Herbert. Dated "8 June-8 July, 1959, Los Angeles."
- Capriccio: for two pianos, celesta, and percussion (three performers) (1962). Ozalid masters, pencil, 76 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Score (62 leaves) and percussion parts (14 leaves). "Los Angeles, 1962"--title page.
- Epiphanies: a theatre piece for 33 performers (1968). Ozalid masters, pencil and typescript, 147 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  "Los Angeles, June 1964-March 1969. Annotations and corrections XII.3.70"--title page. Contents: Film 1; Scene A; Film 2. Includes score and percussion parts for Scene A only.
- Epiphanies (part 2) (1968). Ozalid masters, pencil and typescript, 150 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Contents: Film 3; Scene B; Film 4; Scene C. Score.
- Organum 1-6: for chorus, organ, and percussion (1972/80). Ozalid masters; pencil, ink and typescript. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Organum 1-5, score, 47 leaves; Organum 1-4, score, 23 leaves; Organum 1-5; percussion part, 8 leaves. "Peterborough, 1972 (1 through 5), Los Angeles, 1980 (6)"--title page.
- The God of love love my Shepherd is.. Ozalid masters, pencil and typescript, 4 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Leaves are numbered 38-41. No title. Score, SATB. With Organum 1-6.
- Three Movements, for pianos and percussion (4 performers) (1972, 1975). Ozalid masters, pencil, 42 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  "Peterborough, 1972 (outer movements); Los Angeles, 1975 (middle movement added)"--title page.
- A Midsummer night's dream (1976). Ozalid masters, black ink, 48 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  "Incidental music written for the Theatre Arts production under the direction of Thomas Wheatley.. Los Angeles, 10 Sept-29 Sept 1976"--title page.
- Late Songs, for high voice and piano (1978). Ozalid masters, pencil and black ink, 31 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Includes performance notes and texts.
- Seasons of the Minds, for SATB, piano four-hands and celesta (1980). Ozalid masters, black ink, 69 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Score. Includes explanatory performance notes (1 leaf) and text (1 leaf).
- Saint Joan's music (1980). Ozalid masters, pencil, 18 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  "Written for the 1982 Theatre Arts production of G. B. Shaw's Saint Joan, under the direction of Michael McLain.. Los Angeles, February 4 through 20, 1982."--title page.
- Triplum: for organ and percussion (three performers) (1981). Manuscript (30 l., pencil, black ink, red ink); printed score (23p). (Box 2, Folder 4)
  "Los Angeles, 1981"--typed title page.
- Marriage a la mode: music for the Dryden play (1981). Ozalid masters, pencil, 36 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  "Los Angeles, December 1980."--title page.
- As you like it (1983). Ozalid masters, pencil, 25 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  "Music written for the 1983 Theatre Arts production of Shakespeare's play, under the direction of Thomas Wheatley.. Los Angeles, December 10, 1982 through February 1, 1983"--title page.
- Touch: music for dance, for two keyboards (1984). Manuscript, pencil, 18 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  "Los Angeles, 1984"--title page.
- Baroque Isles, for mallet percussion (2 performers) (1986). Manuscript, pencil, 18 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  For two marimbas and vibraphone (2 performers). Dated March 1986.
- Orpheus, a story with music (1987). Manuscript, pencil and typescript, 24 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  For narrator, piano, synthesizer, percussion. A translation by the composer of Orphee by Jules Supervielle.
- Slowsong, for high voice and piano (1987). Manuscript, pencil and typescript, 15 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- The French Park, for two guitars (1988). Manuscript (pencil, 13p.); printed score (9p., 2 copies). (Box 2, Folder 11)
  "Fall 1988; to Matthew Elgart and Peter Yates"--title page
- The Baroque Isles: the voyage out; for two pianos (1993). Ozalid masters, pencil, 18 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  "The ring and pattern of the island music deteriorate in the air.."--title page.